Shivang Koshti Mobile: 07570433927

Email: Shivang.koshti@yahoo.com

Summary

Demonstrated skills for 13 + years in developing and testing enterprise applications across Banking & Finance, Equity Markets, Multimedia, Infrastructure, Networking, Security and Data- intensive applications. Proficient in various SDLC stages and tools, excelling in creating fully integrated applications. Successfully designed & delivered solutions, positively impacting a number of customers, contributing to increases profits.

SKILLS

- Programming languages: Python & have also worked in NodeJS, JavaScript, Java, shell scripting, SQL, and C.
- Frameworks/Libraries: pandas, PySpark, Fastapi, Flask, Cypress, ROBOT Framework, Gauge, Grafana, Selenium, Cucumber, Postman, Test & Behaviour Driven Designs, JMeter, and Jenkins.
- Development tools: Eclipse, IntelliJ, PyCharm, Maven, GIT, bitbucket, etc.
- Familiar with databases(SQL/NoSQL), messaging(RabbitMQ), Linux scripting, storage, Automation tools(Terraform, Ansible), observability & monitoring (Grafana, Dynatrace), Work flow automation (Apache Airflow, Camunda) & authentication concepts.
- Cloud/Bigdata tools: GCP, AWS(Developer Certified), Containerization (Docker, Kuber-
- netes), Splunk, Hadoop, Spark, HIVE sql, AWS tools lambda, EC2, S3, Athena, Glue, IAM, Data pipeline, SQS, SNS, CloudShell.
- Understanding of CI/CD, Application Resiliency, and Security. Can create CI/CD pipelines using Jenkins and Urbancode.
- Developed applications implementing networking protocols (RIP, OSPF) and used Wireshark, Fiddler, and tcpdump for network testing.
- Hands-on practical experience in system design, application development, testing, SDLC, debugging, code maintenance and operational stability

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer | JPMorgan Chase & Co | Apr 2023 - Present

- Delivered application for daily VDI(virtual desktops Citrix) utilization reporting across regions using FASTAPI, Kubernetes, Docker and Jenkins. And creating a visualization using Grafana/Prometheus.
- Contributed to the development of automation framework for SRE, emphasizing provisioning and managing VDI with the installation of base components.
- Created Grafana dashboard visualizations for metrics across various domains, workgroups, and regions.
- Developed API applications to fetch infrastructure reports for 300K+ employees worldwide.
- Implemented automated application which can scale out to cope with complex large VDI environment having ~21k devices

Senior Consultant | Tata Consultancy Services | Jul 2017 - Mar 2023

- Utilizing Nodejs and Postman for API automation with JavaScript, incorporating BDD Cucumber and Junit5, and conducting UI automation using Cypress.
- Creating an Automation framework with TestComplete and Python for desktop applications.
- Developing an Automation framework on AWS cloud for ETL applications.
- Developed on Hadoop ecosystem/Bigdata testing using PySpark, Hive, Spark, Python, SQL, and implementing end-to-end ETL automation 7 deploying DevOps with UrbanCode & Nexus.
- Worked on Automation Framework for Apache Beam's Dataflow application, deployed on premise and Google Cloud, using Docker and Google Cloud Java API for Storage-Compute-Database, within the Gauge framework.
- Developed a Python-based automation framework for ETL functional testing, employing BDD (Cucumber, Selenium, GIT, Java).
- More Tools: GIT, Maven, Jira, ALM, ControlM, Eclipse IDE, PyCharm, and IntelliJ.
- Achievements: Awarded Innovator award for client in Finance Vertical 2019
- Recognitions from client for a ETL based application thereby helping in migration from on premise to cloud thereby helping client achieve profit & reducing time to market.

Professional Freelance | Freelance (Self-employed) | Feb 2017 – Jul 2017

• Engineered an software application for testing Replication & Migration applications across Physical, Virtual, and cloud-based resources. Tools: GIT, bash scripting, Python, paramiko, file systems, PyCharm.

Software Developer | Nuance Communications | Feb 2016 – Jan 2017

- Spearheaded Python automation for the collection of application reports.
- Oversaw the maintenance of a Python automation framework, encompassing shell and batch scripts.
- Actively involved in both frontend and backend automation testing.
- Conducted F5 Load balancer configuration and testing, specializing in high availability failover/failback scenarios.
- Demonstrated expertise in Linux administration, proficient in configuration, maintenance, and daily usage.

Software Engineer in Test | Symantec | Aug 2015 - Feb 2016

- Developed an TDD automation framework for web application using Selenium, Python, git, splinter, lettuce
 delivering customized reporting on endpoint security software, network access devices and security endpoints
 (Switches, Firewalls) in virtual environments (ESX, VMware).
- Executed tasks involving Active Directory, Certificate Server, VPN, Unix, bash scripting and Remote access.

Software Engineer | eInfochips (An Arrow Company) | Oct 2011 – May 2015

- Created a frontend automation tests using Selenium, shell scripting and Java.
- Developed and provided patches in Java (backend), Adobe Flex (frontend), and shell scripting.
- Resolved customer-raised issues in C code using C Scope, C Tags, make, perforce, VI, TCL scripting, and vim.
- Conducted & team member of application development on validating network testing for L2/L3 protocols, VPN IPSEC, Remote access VPN client, SSL VPN, and AAA.
- Configured & conducted RTP/RTSP video streaming, tested failover scenarios on Firewalls (Active/Standby & Active/Active) and performed load testing of server pages using Jmeter.
- Deployed and tested network services involving Proxy servers, DNS, DHCP, WOWZA streaming server, FTP, and web servers, troubleshooting & debugging to identify memory leaks and resolving performance bottlenecks.
- Achievements: Member of Best Team of Year 2014

Test Engineer | Acktron Security System (P) Ltd. | Oct 2010 – Sep 2011

• Developed and implemented strategies and use cases for security systems and BMS devices, IoT sensors, controllers including interface modules for card readers and biometric systems.

EDUCATION

• Bachelor of Engineering | Electronics and Communication | South Gujarat University, India

CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS Developer Associate Amazon
- Cisco Certified Network Associate Routing and Switching (CCNA) Cisco
- Certified Tester Foundation Level (CTFL) ISTQB